Finding Aid for Raymond F. Clevenger papers, 1953-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Raymond F. Clevenger papers
1953-1967
Clevenger, Raymond Francis, 1926-
85966 Aa 2
Democratic Congressman from Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan, 1965-1966. Correspondence and other papers concerning congressional affairs, natural resources, federal health and welfare programs, and Democratic politics; also material relating to the problems and politics of Michigan's Upper Peninsula.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
46 linear feet
The collection was deposited by Congressman Clevenger (donor no. 4455 ) in 1967.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is closed, except with the written permission of the donor.
Francis Raymond Clevenger was born in Chicago, Illinois, on June 6, 1926. During World War II, he served in the United States Army Medical Corps from July 1944 to July 1946. Upon his return, Clevenger attended Roosevelt University in Chicago and the London School of Economics and Political Science. He graduated from Roosevelt University in 1949 and from the University of Michigan Law School in 1952.
Clevenger began practicing law in Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan in 1953. He early became active in state Democratic party affairs, serving as delegate to the Democratic State conventions in the period of 1954 to 1964. He was also a delegate to the Democratic National Convention in 1956. He was a member of the Democratic State Central Committee from 1958 to 1960. He was also a member of the Michigan Corporation and Securities Commission in the Swainson administration, 1961-1963.
Clevenger was elected as a Democrat to the Eighty-ninth Congress (January 3, 1965-January 3, 1967). He was an unsuccessful candidate for reelection in 1966. He was appointed by President Johnson to serve as chairman of the Great Lakes Basin Commission from 1967 to 1968. He then resumed the practice of law in Ann Arbor, Michigan which he had made his home.
The Raymond Clevenger collection consists mainly of papers from his one term in the US Congress, 1965-1966. There are also a scattering of materials relating to his various campaigns for office and about his work with the Michigan Corporation and Securities Commission. The collection is largely unprocessed.
Subjects:
Clevenger, Raymond Francis, 1926-; Conservation of natural resources--Michigan.; Democratic Party (Mich.); Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Sault Sainte Marie (Mich.); United States. Congress. House.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
- Congressional files
  - Correspondence and other materials, 1965
    - A-B (Box 1)
    - C-F (Box 2)
    - G-P (Box 3)
    - P-W (Box 4)
    - A-H (Box 5)
    - I-P (Box 6)
    - P-U (Box 7)
    - V-W (Box 8)
  - Correspondence and other materials, 1966
    - A-Education (Box 9)
    - Education-F (Box 10)
    - Federal Agencies (Box 11)
    - Federal-Foreign Relations (Box 12)
    - Federal Agencies-House of Representatives (Box 13)
    - Health and Welfare (Box 14)
    - H-L (Box 15)
    - M (Box 16)
    - Military-Natural Resources (Box 17)
    - S-U (Box 20)
    - Veterans Affairs (Box 21)
- Other papers
  (includes Congressional files, campaign materials, and pre-and post-Congressional career activities)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 23)
    (continued)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Correspondence [A-Z], 1965-1966 (Box 25)
  - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 26)
  - Campaign materials, 1964 (Box 27)
  - Legal practice papers, 1953-1963 (Box 30)
  - Papers mainly concerning Congressional affairs, 1955-1966 (Box 31)
  - Papers concerning political campaign and legal practice, 1959-1964 (Box 34)
  - Papers concerning legal practice, 1959-1964 (Box 35)
  - Papers concerning campaign background; include mailing lists, 1960-1964 (Box 36)
  - Miscellaneous and invitations, 1960-1966 (Box 37)
  - Papers concerning legal practice, 1961-1964 (Box 39)
  - Papers, 1963-1965 (Box 45)
  - Papers concerning Michigan politics, 1964-1966 (Box 47)
  - Papers concerning Congressional matters, 1965 (Box 48)
  - Papers concerning Congressional matters, 1965 (Box 49)
  - Papers, concerning UPCAP, 1965-1966 (Box 53)
  - Papers concerning public works, 1966 (Box 55)
  - Papers concerning legislation, 1966 (Box 56)
  - Papers concerning nominations for military academies and social security cases, 1966-1967 (Box 57)
  - Pamphlets and books mainly concerning recreation in Michigan, 1963-1966 (Box 59)
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed: political and campaign files, Michigan Corporation and Securities Commission activities (Box 60)
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed: political and campaign files, Michigan Corporation and Securities Commission activities (Box 61)
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed: political and campaign files, Michigan Corporation and Securities Commission activities (Box 62)
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed: political and campaign files, Michigan Corporation and Securities Commission activities (Box 63)
  - Miscellaneous unprocessed: political and campaign files, Michigan Corporation and Securities Commission activities (Box 64)